<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frank Peng</title>
    <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frank Peng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:25:52 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utsfpeng.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework Wk 2</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/homework-wk-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:25:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/homework-wk-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 - Homework Problem Statement A realistic and achievable goal that I set for myself is to gain fundamentals skills in pen-testing, so that I am able to have a solid skill set that I can build upon after the studio to go towards a future career in cyber security.
Developing the basic mindset of being curious about errors and also how to actually go about testing. E.g. * Checking Source Code * Going through Robots.txt * Checking HTTP GET/POST Requests and their Responses. * Directory traversing * Looking for any access control misconfigurations * XSS injection into all the input fields, especially search bar * SQL injection into login screen input fields.
Currently, I have zero knowledge of Cyber Security in regards to what tools and techniques to use for pen-testing and I want to improve my general ability to detect web application security vulnerabilities.
I have been recommended PicoCTF, HackTheBox, natas and bandits (Wargames) to start myself on the journey of learning.
Also the resources recommended in this week for web penetration skills development include: * Web for Pentester * WebGoat * Natas * Shellter Labs * Root Me
Ref: https://utscyber.studio/learn/Week%202%20-%20Feb%2011/
Possible milestones to my goal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-1-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 21:43:34 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-1-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 Reflection (Sprint 1) Introduction Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Frank Peng! I&amp;rsquo;m currently a 5th year Software Engineering Student at UTS. I am undertaking a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Engineering with Honours and a Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice (C09067v2 - B Eng DipProfEngPrac). I am majoring in ICT Engineering and sub-majoring in Software.
I have always had a strong interest towards Cyber Security since the start of my university degree and I have thought about the possibility of pursuing the Cyber Security field as a potential future career when I graduate. However, I have struggled trying to find a way to start and get involved for a long time, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t had as much exposure to the Cyber Security space as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked.
I chose to undertake the UTS MIDAS Summer Studio 2019 subject and join the Cyber Security Studio as a way to get my hands dirty and begin my journey towards learning about Cyber Security and acquire the skills and experience needed to get me started. I hope to use everything I learn in the studio as a starting point to allow me to continue learning more after building a foundational background in the field.
  Picture of me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:23:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>My very first experience with Markdown I have not had any prior experience with writing markdown, but this is my first attempt at doing so.
It seems to follow a logical structure and have very intuitive and common sense based formatting, so it almost feels like natural language based format when writing. However, there are still a few things that I am trying to confirm, such as code formatting especially when I&amp;rsquo;m writing actual sections or pieces of code on the website.
In addition, I was also advised that I can write pure html as well, it may come especially handy for iframes and also other embedded based html code. Furthermore, I am still getting accustomed to creating tables.
Plans for how I am going to construct this website for UTS MIDAS Summer Studio 2019.
 Home = Home page Blog = Reflections (Weekly Reflections, as part of the requirements for Cyber Security Studio) + SLOs (Addressing all the Subject Learning Outcomes for the studio) Portfolio = End of Studio Deliverable About = Brief Summary about myself and the website.  Going to try and learn python and learn how to use Kali Linux to explore cyber security concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>