<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Frank Peng</title>
    <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Frank Peng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 01:35:16 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-03/week-4-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 01:35:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-03/week-4-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 Reflection (Sprint 4) Week 4 has been a very eventful week, full of challenges and accomplishments. It is also the last week of UTS MIDAS Summer Studio 2019 and I have nothing but great things to say about this Cyber Security studio which has helped me to learn about Cyber Security from scratch. It has been nothing short of amazing and I did not expect a summer studio to not only push me so far out of my comfort zone but also teach me more than I can ever imagine.
We started the week off with Reverse Engineering with Ruben Thijssen, a speaker/presenter from Symantec. He presented us with a series of challenges that we had to solve that involved working with assembly instructions and binary files.
More on that over at: http://frankpeng.me/blog/2019-02/reverse-engineering/
Afterwards, we were encouraged to go from &amp;ldquo;Boot2Root&amp;rdquo; on a vulnerable machine. An extra level of difficulty was to work on ones which have no write-ups/walkthroughs. Hence, we did an active vulnerable machine on Hack The Box called . This involved using a variety of network-based tools to discover ports and services being used. In addition, we had to utilise reverse shells for privilege escalation and a lot of trial and error in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/reverse-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 10:24:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/reverse-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Reverse Engineering Today we were introduced to Reverse Engineering by Ruben Thijssen, a Application Security Manager from Symantec.
He demonstrated the use of Binary Ninja to reverse engineer high-level language ( C ) and disassemble it into Assembly Language.
He gave us a set of introductory challenges to reverse engineering and binary exploitation.
The session itself challenged us to think outside the box and be strategic at what we look for.
We were exposed to new tools such as Binary Ninja, GDB (GNU Debugger), PEDA (Python Exploit Development Assistance) and the use of x86 Opcode and Instruction Reference.
It was unlike anything I have ever seen. I really wanted to pick his brain since he had such a vase understanding of how systems work to a very low level perspective. He was able to recognise structures from the back of his hand and develop an idea of a problem from brief descriptions. It was amazing to see such mastery of assembly language.
0x01 - Abradolf Lincler Challenge The first challenge that he posed to use was called &amp;ldquo;0x01 - Abradolf Lincler&amp;rdquo;. This involved investigating a binary file which contains a hidden flag that we need to find in order to complete the challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-3-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 21:07:14 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-3-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Week 3 Reflection (Sprint 3) Week 3 was quite an intensive week at the Cyber Security Summer Studio. We became more focused on improving our practical cyber security skills with real world testing, a variety of vulnerable VMs and taking on different cyber security challenges.
On Monday, we started off the week with a Free For All session and I catched up with David. David had tried API testing on the industry sponsor&amp;rsquo;s website: . He tried checking robots.txt, bit swapping with a similar username to one that may exist (e.g. rupport instead of support and then flipping the bit). Furthermore, he also tried out brute forcing and also trying out different ways to get into admin. In addition, his testing led him to find out that the version of nginx that the industry sponsor&amp;rsquo;s website was using and found CVE details that reveal things can could be exploited.
After the Free-For-All session, our studio facilitators took on our feedback and worked on improving our studio for the better based on the feedback that they received. As a student of the studio, it is really reassuring to know that the studio facilitators are putting in so much effort into the studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tryhackme Mr Robot Journey</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/tryhackme-mr-robot-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 15:25:40 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/tryhackme-mr-robot-journey/</guid>
      <description>Tryhackme Mr Robot Journey I attempted the Tryhackme Mr Robot Machine/CTF.
First off, I had to set up the network to deploy the Mr. Robot virtual machine.
I went to the access page and downloaded my configuration file and then downloaded the OpenVPN Source (in .zip file).
When I was following the commands given in INSTALL or README file:
 ./configure make make-install  During the ./configure command, it encountered errors.
configure: error: openssl check failed
I searched the error and found a stackoverflow article.
Ref: https://superuser.com/questions/371901/openssl-missing-during-configure-how-to-fix
I used the command suggested.
sudo apt-get install libssl-dev
However, even after installing that package, it still did not work.
Upon further inspection, the How to Connect? section, I saw that there was a difference between the general commands and the ones suggested.
Trying the other commands that were suggested. Replacing &amp;lsquo;username&amp;rsquo; with the actual username.
sudo apt install openvpn sudo openvpn username.ovpn
After entering those commands in, I successfully connected to the network.
Once I connected to the network, I deployed the machine to find the 3 keys.
I typed the ip address into the web browser and loaded the page up. At first I thought it was wrong, but after a second refresh of the page, I realised that the page was intentionally jet black for a reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-2-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:18:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-2-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 - Reflection (Sprint 2) In the Cyber Security Summer Studio this week, our primary focus was on Web Application Security.
Firstly, we started off with a Scrum meeting around the room for each studio member on what we worked on, what we want to work on and our current obstacles. It was very interesting to find some studio members going above and beyond and have acquired such great amounts of experience in such a short period of time. Personally, I was working on Natas and wanted to finish Natas off and move onto the other resources that the studio facilitators (Larry, Darsh, Luke) have provided us with. My current obstacles were mainly technical issues with a bit of a time management issue. However, I hope to improve that moving forward by doing more research and also organising my time better with my schedule on my calendar and prioritisation. (SLO 4 + SLO 5)
We were introduced to some of the most common web application security vulnerabilities that currently exist, which include: CSRF (Cross Site Request Forgery), XSS (Cross Site Scripting) and SQLi (Structured Query Language Injection).
CSRF is an attack that forces the user to perform an unwanted action and generally uses state-changing requests since it requires tricking a victim to click on a link or execute an action on behalf of the attacker while the user is authenticated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revised Problem Statement</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/revised-problem-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 21:18:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/revised-problem-statement/</guid>
      <description>Revised Problem Statement &amp;ldquo;Web Applications have become an everyday essential, but most lack sufficient cyber security measures.&amp;rdquo;
Web Applications have become a quintessential sales channel for any business and a revenue driver for eCommerce organisations. However, when building a web application for most businesses, security is not at the forefront of the development process, leading to exposed security vulnerabilities to their business&amp;rsquo; most important assets.
By investigating security vulnerabilities on modern web applications and researching on the resources &amp;amp; material available, I hope to discover the impacts that the OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks can have on a modern web application, with regards to Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability.
In 2017, eCommerce was responsible for $2.3 trillion dollars in sales and expected to grow to $4.5 trillion in 2021. (Hatch 2018) Hence, it is a very attractive target for Cyber criminals to focus on and try to make a profit from. Hence, it is pivotal that everything needs to be done to protect these web applications from cyber security vulnerabilities and attacks. Hence, I would like to research on the different attack vectors and solutions available for implementation to prevent disruption to these increasingly significant services from Cyber Security threats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webappsec Statement</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/webappsec-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 01:49:06 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/webappsec-statement/</guid>
      <description>Web Application Security - Problem Statement For submission on Friday 15-02-2019
Current Problem Statement on WebAppSec In Web Application Security, my goal is to learn how to identify common web vulnerabilities and develop a habit/mindset on checking for them first, so that I can do something akin to a process of elimination and work out what flaws and vulnerabilities that a website may have.
Currently, I still feel that I do not have a grasp on what to look for and haven&amp;rsquo;t developed the habit or &amp;ldquo;muscle-memory&amp;rdquo; for discovering common web vulnerabilities. As such, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a logical order of doing the basic steps to eliminate the potential likelihood that common vulnerabilities may exist.
In order to close this knowledge gap, my solution is to start off working on the Natas challenges till I reach the end (if possible) and potentially look at the other resources suggested (WebGoat, Web for Pentester, Shellter Labs and Root Me). In addition, I might try working on Hack The Box and Try Hack Me (Mr Robot), when I feel that I have the basics down and feel comfortable that my skill level can attempt it.
In Natas so far, I&amp;rsquo;ve went through a few levels and discovered a pattern of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natas Journey</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/natas-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 18:04:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/natas-journey/</guid>
      <description>Natas Journey Natas 0 Natas 0 presented a description stating &amp;ldquo;You can find the password for the next level on this page.&amp;rdquo;
First instinct was to look in the source code for hints.
Found the password written in plain-text within HTML comment tags.
Natas 1 Natas 1 presented a challenge with right-click being blocked. On Google Chrome, I used Developer Tools &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Inspect Element to circumvent the issue and checked the source code.
Found the password written in plain-text within HTML comment tags like the previous level.
Natas 2 Natas 2 stated &amp;ldquo;There is nothing on this page.&amp;rdquo;
Checked Source Code and found a random image source pointing to a path: &amp;ldquo;files/pixel.png&amp;rdquo;.
Checked the pixel.png file and found nothing. So went directory traversing back up into the &amp;ldquo;files&amp;rdquo; directory and it listed the index, which revealed a users.txt file.
natas3 password was written in plain-text.
Natas 3 Just like the previous challenge, Natas 3 stated &amp;ldquo;There is nothing on this page.&amp;rdquo;
Within the Source Code, HTML Comments claim &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Not even Google will find it this time&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Challenge Accepted!
  Besides finding it directly using Google, if we check &amp;ldquo;robots.txt&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;
  It shows that there is a Disallow for a path to &amp;ldquo;/s3cr3t/&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework Wk 2</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/homework-wk-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:25:52 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/homework-wk-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 - Homework Problem Statement A realistic and achievable goal that I set for myself is to gain fundamentals skills in pen-testing, so that I am able to have a solid skill set that I can build upon after the studio to go towards a future career in cyber security.
Developing the basic mindset of being curious about errors and also how to actually go about testing. E.g. * Checking Source Code * Going through Robots.txt * Checking HTTP GET/POST Requests and their Responses. * Directory traversing * Looking for any access control misconfigurations * XSS injection into all the input fields, especially search bar * SQL injection into login screen input fields.
Currently, I have zero knowledge of Cyber Security in regards to what tools and techniques to use for pen-testing and I want to improve my general ability to detect web application security vulnerabilities.
I have been recommended PicoCTF, HackTheBox, natas and bandits (Wargames) to start myself on the journey of learning.
Also the resources recommended in this week for web penetration skills development include: * Web for Pentester * WebGoat * Natas * Shellter Labs * Root Me
Ref: https://utscyber.studio/learn/Week%202%20-%20Feb%2011/
Possible milestones to my goal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 Reflection</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-1-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 21:43:34 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/week-1-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 Reflection (Sprint 1) Introduction Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Frank Peng! I&amp;rsquo;m currently a 5th year Software Engineering Student at UTS. I am undertaking a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Engineering with Honours and a Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice (C09067v2 - B Eng DipProfEngPrac). I am majoring in ICT Engineering and sub-majoring in Software.
I have always had a strong interest towards Cyber Security since the start of my university degree and I have thought about the possibility of pursuing the Cyber Security field as a potential future career when I graduate. However, I have struggled trying to find a way to start and get involved for a long time, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t had as much exposure to the Cyber Security space as I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked.
I chose to undertake the UTS MIDAS Summer Studio 2019 subject and join the Cyber Security Studio as a way to get my hands dirty and begin my journey towards learning about Cyber Security and acquire the skills and experience needed to get me started. I hope to use everything I learn in the studio as a starting point to allow me to continue learning more after building a foundational background in the field.
  Picture of me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Blog Post</title>
      <link>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:23:18 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://utsfpeng.github.io/blog/2019-02/first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>My very first experience with Markdown I have not had any prior experience with writing markdown, but this is my first attempt at doing so.
It seems to follow a logical structure and have very intuitive and common sense based formatting, so it almost feels like natural language based format when writing. However, there are still a few things that I am trying to confirm, such as code formatting especially when I&amp;rsquo;m writing actual sections or pieces of code on the website.
In addition, I was also advised that I can write pure html as well, it may come especially handy for iframes and also other embedded based html code. Furthermore, I am still getting accustomed to creating tables.
Plans for how I am going to construct this website for UTS MIDAS Summer Studio 2019.
 Home = Home page Blog = Reflections (Weekly Reflections, as part of the requirements for Cyber Security Studio) + SLOs (Addressing all the Subject Learning Outcomes for the studio) Portfolio = End of Studio Deliverable About = Brief Summary about myself and the website.  Going to try and learn python and learn how to use Kali Linux to explore cyber security concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>